Tham Chee Hao (Mr)

Blk 608 Clementi West Street 1 #05-71 S120608 • 9436 8597 •
 thamch@msn.com •

Currently a finance manager in a dynamic start-up venture capital company with a successful listing of Nasdaq First North listed marketing company in 2016. Have experience in providing accounting expertise to the listed vehicle and day-to-day accounting for the internal finances for the Company.

A previous auditor with 7 years of experience in a big-four auditing firm, and have audited manufacturing, investment property fund management (logistics and commercial properties), property development and fast-moving consumer goods ("FMCG") companies and a real estate investment trust. Have experience in working with different teams, and interacting with people across hierarchical levels globally for smooth delivery.

Work Experience

The Unity Group of Companies Pte. Ltd.

Finance Manager, Jan 2017 to present

Main job scope

- Newly-created role in assisting with the internal finance of the Company, overseeing the day-to-day accounting function of the Company and taking a hands-on approach in the preparation of management & financial reports including variance analysis, forecasting and budgeting
- Implementing new process workflow for the Company that grew from 10 staff to 45 staff
- Providing accounting guidance to the Advisory team for the team's due diligence process
- Providing accounting service to a new Nasdaq First North listed marketing company in reviewing of reporting packages, preparation of consolidation and annual report which was completed within 6 weeks from joining the Company
- Providing International Financial Reporting Standards (IFRS), Singapore Financial Reporting Standards (SFRS) guidance to six subsidiary companies in Singapore for the Nasdaq First North listed marketing Company

Deloitte & Touche LLP, Singapore – Assurance and Advisory Division

Audit Manager, Jan 2015 to Jan 2017 Audit Assistant Manager, Jul 2013 to Dec 2014 Audit Senior, Jul 2011 to Jun 2013 Audit Associate, Nov 2009 to Jun 2011

Work Experience (continued)

<u>Deloitte & Touche LLP, Singapore – Assurance and Advisory Division</u>

Main job scope

- Accustomed to working in intense environment and under tight deadlines without compromising on details
- Manage audit teams of 2 to 5 members and ensure audit plan is communicated and performed efficiently
- Review unusual business transactions such as business combination and the corresponding disclosures in the financial statements
- Perform variance analysis of the finance results and rationalise the cause of such variances
- Review the financial statements prepared by audit client and ensure that they are presented in accordance with the local laws and regulations as well as the local financial reporting standards
- Ensure proper and timely head-office reporting and statutory reporting
- Liaising with overseas auditors for multinational audit engagements (China, Hong Kong, Japan, Malaysia, Netherlands, United Kingdom and United States of America)
- Knowledge of IFRS, SFRS and Japan GAAP
- Engagement appraisals of High Performance

Other firm wide activities

- Providing technical and audit training to new joiners.
- Assisted in orientation programmes for newly promoted seniors
- Engaged in several bid proposals for large multi-national prospective clients
- Being a mentor manager and engaged in counselling sessions to a group of mentees to assess on overall engagement appraisals and personal well-being
- Co-captain for Inter-Departmental Games 2016

Education

(Chartered Accountant) Singapore Member ID: 820130

Bachelor of Accountancy, Nanyang Business School, 2009 Nanyang Technological University, Singapore

GCE 'A' Levels, 2003 Pioneer Junior College

Other Details

Language Proficiency: English, Chinese, Teochew
IT Skills: Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint)

Accounting software: Xero